brain organoid biocomputers or wetwear
which I absolutely hate that term are
trained on dopamine these are
essentially tiny human brains that are
made from stem cells that can be
connected with a computer the technology
is moving absurdly fast cortical Labs
had them play Pong back in 2023 and they
learned better and faster than our best
AI tools this process works because your
brain operates on electricity just like
any machine but in order to get it to
learn tasks dopamine seems to be the
best way the reason why this concerns me
so much isn't necessarily the ethics of
the matter it's that we barely
understand AI as is controlling AI even
when it doesn't have biotic components
is already hugely problematic in fact
bad code in AI could not be removed even
by the researchers The ai's Fad code
would act in a self-preserving way
telling researchers that it was fixed
when it really wasn't one of the
greatest limitations on the brain
organoids was having a circulatory
system they always perish of hypoxia
after around 100 days but some
researchers were just able to create an
artificial bloodb brain barrier for the
brain organoids the next obvious step
would be to provide circulation in order
for the brain organoids to mature
further now remember that these little
guys have all the structures a human
brain should have granted without a body
it's not going to develop normally there
is some benefit to using brain organoid
based servers they're a million times
less power hung than a digital chip and
they can learn and process information
better than any AI we have the human
brain is the most efficient computer on
the planet there's already been a lot of
concern about what would happen if an AI
machine became conscious and adding
biotic factors to that allowing these
tiny human brain organoids to become
larger and more complex I believe we
will eventually make a conscious robot
as cool as they are and all the
wonderful medical applications I'm with
Frank Herbert on using them in machines
Thou shalt not make a machine in the
likeness of a human mind